Zankoku na tenshi no you ni
Just like the cruel angel
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
2D4U PRESENTS:
Aoi kaze ga ima
Even though the untested breeze...
mune no doa o tataitemo
...taps at the door to your heart
Watashi dake o tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata
You just look solely at me and smile
Sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuu de
So intent on seeking out that gentle touch
Unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi
Such innocent eyes, still ignorant of their destiny
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
But someday, you are sure to realize...
sono senaka ni wa
...that upon your back
Haruka mirai mezasu tame
You have the wings with which to fly...
no hane ga aru koto
...towards the distant future
Zankoku na tenshi no teeze
The cruel angel's thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobidatsu
Soon, you will take flight from the windowsill
Hotobashiru atsui patosu de
With your torrent of ardent pathos
Omoide o uragiru nara
If you are to betray our memories
Kono sora o daite kagayaku
You, who embrace these heavens and shine
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
15 YEARS AGO
YEAR 2000 A.D.
Father...
EPISODE 12
THE VALUE OF A MIRACLE
Thanks, Shinji, you really saved us
from the rain.
Where's Miss Misato?
I guess she must still be asleep.
She's been working all night recently.
That's right, she has a tough job.
Let's keep it quiet so that we don't wake her up.
What are you guys doing here?!
Taking shelter from the rain.
You sure you guys aren't after me?
Well, I'm changing, so if you peep, I'll kill you!
Shut up, ya idiot!
Who'd wanna see ya changin' clothes?!
She's way too self-conscious.
Sorry for disturbing you!
Well, welcome, you two.
I see you're back. We've got a harmonics test
tonight, so don't be late.
Right.
Did you hear that, Asuka?
Yes, Ma'am!
Congratulations on your promotion!
Congratulations!
Thank you.
You're most welcome.
Well, see you later.
See you!
What's up? Did something happen
to Miss Misato?
Didn't you see her collar tab?
The number of lines increased to two.
That means that she's been promoted
from captain to major.
Really? I didn't notice that.
Yeah, I wonder when...
Are ya serious? You guys are pathetic!
Don't you two have any compassion?
You know, it's a tough job for someone so young
to foster two junior high kids!
We're the only ones who've got
any human compassion.
Units 00 and 02 are both on the edge
of the contamination zone.
They've reached their limit.
Unit 01 can still tolerate
a little more though, can't he?
Lower the graph depth another 0.3.
He's almost reached the contamination zone.
And he's still getting these readings? Incredible.
His harmonics and sync rate are
also catching up with Asuka's.
Is this what you call a gift, I wonder?
It's like he was born to pilot an Eva.
Even if he doesn't want to.
I doubt that'll make him happy.
Good work, you three.
Shinji, you did well.
What do you mean?
Your harmonics value increased by
eight points since the last test.
That's very good.
But it's still fifty points lower than mine!
Yes, but it's eight points in ten days.
That's impressive.
That's not impressive!
Isn't that great?
Such words of praise for you!
I'm going on ahead, idiot!
...and that was a postcard from
"Mr. Wah" of Tokyo-2.
But you know, don't get all sulky
because you got dumped by a girl.
Congratulations on your promotion.
Thanks.
When I was a kid, this area
was filled with barracks
But to be honest, I'm not really all that thrilled.
And we were just grateful
if we got to eat that day.
I can understand that.
Getting praised like earlier doesn't make me
all that happy either.
We didn't have the leisure to do anything
about the people we liked.
All it does is make Asuka angry.
Our parents are safe and food isn't a problem,
so we have a lot to be thankful for in this era.
I wonder why she got mad?
We live in a great time in which
we can really enjoy happiness.
What did I do wrong?
That bothers you?
You got that, Mr. Wah?
Yes.
That's because all you ever do is worry
about what other people think.
Congratulations
On Your Promotion
Celebration Spot
Reserved Today
Congratulations!
Thanks, guys!
Thank you, Suzuhara.
Nah. He's the one who came up with this.
That's right! I, Kensuke Aida was the planner!
Kensuke Aida!
Thank you, Aida.
Oh, no, all I did was what
anybody would have done!
But why's the class rep here?
Because I invited her.
Right?
What about Rei?
Of course I invited her,
but that girl's unsociable.
Man, Mr. Kaji's so late.
Is Mr. Kaji really that cool?
Totally!
He's so much better than these dorks
that it's like night and day.
It's an insult to compare him to them.
What'd ya say?!
Let's hear that again!
Is it still difficult for you to be
in this kind of situation?
I'm okay.
I'm just not used to being with
so many people.
Why do they have to be so noisy?
A promotion...
That means that people have
acknowledged your work, right?
Yeah, I suppose.
That's why they're happy.
But it doesn't make you happy?
Oh, it's not like I'm not happy. I am, a little.
But that's not the reason I work here.
Then why did you join Nerv?
Well, it's been so long that I forgot.
That's got to be Mr. Kaji!
I came directly from HQ. We just
happened to meet on the way.
That's rather suspicious.
Oh, are you jealous?
As if.
Anyway, I'd like to offer my congratulations,
Major Katsuragi.
I guess I can't gripe to you anymore.
What are you trying to say, you jerk?
But anyway, it's unprecedented
for both the Commander and Vice Commander
to leave Japan together.
That just shows how they trust you
to hold down the fort while they're gone.
My father's not here?
Commander Ikari is at the South Pole right now.
The South Pole, a world of death
which permits no life to exist.
Or should I simply call it Hell?
Nevertheless, we, mankind, are here.
We're living things, and we're alive.
That's because we're under the
protection of science.
Science is the power of man.
That arrogance is what caused the tragedy
of fifteen years ago, the Second Impact.
And here is the end result.
This is a greater punishment than we deserve.
This is truly the Dead Sea.
Yet this is a world that has been purified,
purged of the original sin.
I'd prefer a world where people live,
no matter how stained with sin.
Reporting. Telegram received
from Nerv Headquarters.
An Angel has been detected in orbit
above the Indian Ocean.
It appeared suddenly, two minutes ago.
Search Satellite 6 moving to that orbit.
Two minutes to contact.
We have video of the target.
That's impressive.
Now that's just ridiculous.
Closing on target.
Start search.
Data transmission commencing.
Reception confirmed.
Commencing analysis.
Was that an AT Field?
It's a new way of using it.
What incredible destructive power.
That's an AT Field!
It's using kinetic energy too.
It's like this Angel is a bomb in and of itself.
In any case, the first blast was way off
and hit the Pacific.
And two hours later,
the second shot struck there.
Since then, it has been steadily
adjusting for error.
That means it's learning.
Photo:
Search Satellite 7
Maximum Magnification
N2 aerial mines had no effect on it either.
The Angel's movements
since then are unknown.
It's probably coming here.
Yes, and next time it'll drop itself.
So, that will give us a third Ashinoko Lake?
All five Fuji Lakes will be fused into
a single body linked to the Pacific,
taking Headquarters with it.
What about Commander Ikari?
We're unable to contact him
due to the Angel's powerful jamming.
What is the Magi's judgment?
They unanimously agree
in recommending evacuation.
What will you do?
You're the one who's in charge now.
Notify all of the Japanese government ministries.
Under special declaration D-17,
provided for under Nerv's authority,
all residents within radius of 50km
are to evacuate immediately.
Ask Matsushiro to back up the Magi.
We're abandoning this location?
No, but it's not necessary
to place everyone at risk.
A D-17 Special Declaration has been
made by the government.
All Lanes Outgoing
All residents must evacuate to their
designated locations.
Beginning with the 6th and 7th blocks,
move according to your district chief's
direction immediately.
The evacuation of the city is complete.
In accordance with Department Alert C,
the evacuation of noncombatants and
D class personnel has been completed.
You're going to do this? Seriously?
Yes, I am.
You're going to throw away all three Evas
with your selfish decision?
The chance of success is only 0.00001%!
That's not even one in ten thousand!
It's not zero. I'm just banking on the Evas.
Major Katsuragi!
I am currently in charge.
I want to do whatever I can.
Destroying Angels is my duty.
Your duty? Don't make me laugh.
This is for your own sake, isn't it?
Your revenge against the Angels!
WHAAAAAAT?
Catch it in our hands?
That's right. We'll position the Evas
in the estimated drop zone.
You'll catch it while maintaining your
AT Fields at full strength.
What if the Angel is far off course?
We'll be out of luck, then.
What if the Evas aren't able
to withstand the impact?
We're out of luck then too.
Our chance of success?
God only knows, is all I can say.
If we succeed, it'll truly be a miracle.
The only miracles with any value
are the ones you work.
Meaning, make it work somehow?
I'm sorry, but we have no other options
for this operation.
How can you call this an operation?!
You're right, we really can't.
So if you don't want to, you can refuse.
Are you all okay with this?
Regulations say you're technically supposed
to write a will. What do you want to do?
That's fine, I don't plan on needing one.
I'm fine too. I have no need.
I'm also fine.
I'm sorry.
Once this is over, I'll treat everyone
to a steak dinner!
What? Really?
I promise.
Yay!
Don't forget!
You can count on it.
So I suppose steak defines a great dinner.
Does she think a kid these days
would be impressed with steak?
That's why I say the Second Impact generation
has really cheap standards.
She can't help it.
What was with that "Yay!"?
Pretending you're so happy!
If it helps Miss Misato feel good about
being in command, what's wrong with that?
Now, since she's going to treat us,
Tokyo Gourmet
I wonder where we should have her take us?
You're coming with us this time.
I'm not going.
Why not?
I don't like meat.
Because of the Angel's radio disturbance,
the target has been lost.
We can't determine the exact location,
but based on the data up until we lost it,
the estimated point of impact
calculated by the Magi
is here.
The range is this wide?
The distance from one side
to the other is enormous.
Given the size of the target's AT Field,
it could totally annihilate HQ by hitting
anywhere in this zone.
Given that, we'll station the Evas
at each of these three points.
On what grounds is this dispersal based?
Intuition.
Intuition?
Yes, a woman's intuition.
How slipshod!
I can see our miracle getting further
and further away.
Miss Misato has never won the lottery.
Say...
What?
Asuka, why do you pilot an Eva?
To exhibit my talent to the world, of course.
You mean to prove that you exist?
Yeah, something like that.
You're not going to ask her?
I've asked Ayanami before.
My, how intimate the two of you are.
It's not like that.
Then what about you, Shinji?
I don't know.
You don't know? What are you, stupid?
Maybe I am.
You really are stupid.
One hundred twenty minutes
to estimated time of impact.
You all evacuate too.
I can take care of this myself.
No, this is our job as well.
We can't let the kids risk
their lives by themselves.
They'll be fine.
Even if the Evas are badly damaged,
their AT Fields will protect the kids.
Inside an Eva is the safest place to be.
Shinji, yesterday you asked me
why I joined Nerv.
My father was a man who lived
for his research,
for his dreams, to the exclusion of all else.
I could never forgive him for that.
I even hated him.
Just like my father.
He never took care of me,
my mother or the family.
His friends always said he was
very sensitive and delicate.
But the truth was that he was just a weak person
running away from reality,
the reality called his family.
He was like a kid.
I readily agreed with my mother
when she decided to divorce him,
because she was always crying.
It seemed to have come as a shock to him,
but at the time, I laughed at him because I felt
he'd brought it on himself.
But he sacrificed himself to
save my life at the end.
Back during the Second Impact.
Then, I didn't know whether I hated him
or loved him.
The only thing that was clear to me
was I wanted to destroy the Angels
who caused the Second Impact.
So in order to do that, I joined Nerv.
In the end, maybe I just want to
get revenge on my father,
so that I can free myself of him.
I mustn't run away. I mustn't run away.
I mustn't run away.
Right.
I must not run away.
Target has been sighted
at maximum magnification.
Distance is approximately 25,000.
Here it comes.
All Evas, start positions.
All we have is a rough estimated trajectory
from optical sightings.
So the Magi will guide you until
the distance is 10,000 meters.
After that, use your own judgment.
I'm leaving it all to you.
Maximum Magnification
Relay: Optical observation Post 3
Angel approaching, approximate
distance 20,000.
Commence operation.
Here we go.
Start!
Distance 12,000!
Field at maximum!
Unit 02! Field to maximum!
I'm doing it!
Now!
Bastard!
Our wireless communications
have been restored.
We're receiving a message from
Commander Ikari at the South Pole.
Connect him here.
Yes, Ma'am.
I'm very sorry, Sir.
My selfish decision has caused
Unit 01 to incur damage.
The responsibility is entirely mine.
That is not a problem.
Destroying Angels is the Evas' purpose.
In fact, we are fortunate to have sustained
such minimal damage.
Yes, excellent work, Major Katsuragi.
Thank you, Sir.
By the way, is the pilot of Unit 01 there?
Yes, Sir!
I've received the report. Good work, Shinji.
Yes, Sir.
Now, Major Katsuragi, I'll leave
the rest in your hands.
Yes, Sir.
All Lanes Incoming
New Tokyo-3 Loop 7
Next station is New Miyanoshita,
New Miyanoshita.
The exit will switch to the left side
at the next station.
Now you're going to have to keep your promise.
Of course!
I withdrew a fortune, so I can even handle
a full-course dinner.
Though it's before payday...
Ramen
We know the state of your wallet.
You can take it easy.
And Miss Perfect said she'd join us
if it was for ramen noodles.
I'll have a garlic ramen with no roast pork.
I'll have shark fin with roast pork. Large!
There you go, one shark fin with roast pork!
Say, Miss Misato?
What?
When I heard my father's words earlier,
I think I finally understood what it's like
to feel happy when you're praised.
And I also realized
that maybe I pilot the Eva because I wanted
to hear those words from him.
You're piloting for something like that?
You really are stupid.
TO BE CONTINUED
PREVIEW
An incident occurs during
a simulation plug experiment,
the underground faciities are corrupted
one after another,
and finally Nerv is confronted with making
the decision to self-destruct.
Next episode: "Angel Invasion"
And expect more fan service next time too!
ANGEL INVASION